* +
*  

×

#### Member Log In

American Academy of Dental Sleep Medicine
-----------------------------------------

AADSM Privacy Policy

AADSM Privacy Policy
====================

Last updated: October 2022  
  
**Introduction**  
  
We at AADSM ("AADSM", "we", "us", and "our") know that your privacy is important. This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) is designed to assist you in understanding how we will process your personally identifiable information (“Personal Data”) on our website located at aadsm.org (the “Website”).  
  
Please read this Policy to learn more about the ways in which we collect and use your Personal Data. If we make any material changes to this Policy, we will notify you in accordance with the process described in the Changes to This Policy section below. By signing up for our services and by using our Website, you consent to our collection, use, disclosure, and all other types of processing of your Personal Data, as described in this Policy.  
  
**Data Controllership**  
  
In the context of this Policy, we act as a data controller for the Personal Data that we process.  
  
**Basis of Processing**  
  
Within the scope of this Policy, we may rely on one or more of the following legal grounds for processing of your Personal Data:

* your consent;
* the need to perform our obligations under a contract or to perform related pre-contractual duties;
* the legitimate interests pursued by us, such as to recruit new members; and
* any other ground, as required or permitted by law in the specific respective context.

Please note that you may withdraw your consent at any time by visiting [https://www.memberleap.com/members/contactus\_page.php?org\_id=adsm&gdpr=Y](https://www.memberleap.com/members/contactus_page.php?org_id=adsm&gdpr=Y). This will not affect the lawfulness of processing, based on consent before the withdrawal.  
  
Where you provide us Personal Data with regard to the performance of a contract, we require this information to be able to enter into a contract with you.  
  
**Categories of Personal Data**  
  
Personal Data collected by us could include:

* contact information, such as first and last name, e-mail address, phone number, and residence address;
* events attendance data;
* online store purchases;
* sponsorship commitments;
* proposal system submissions; and
* any other type of information we may ask you for or that you may choose to provide us with.

**How We Receive Personal Data**  
  
We may receive your Personal Data through our Website. In particular, we receive Personal Data when:

* you sign up as a member of our association using our Website;
* you interact with our Website when, for example, registering for an event; or
* your information that you have provide to us by any other means is entered into our system by us, e.g., for the purpose of sending email newsletters.

We may also receive your personal data from third parties, in which case, we will notify you, where required by applicable laws, without undue delay.  
  
**Purposes of Processing**  
  
We may process your Personal Data for the purposes of:

* registering you as a member of our association;
* enabling your use of the features of our Website;
* handling dues and fee billings for membership, events, and other association business;
* retaining statistical information about your involvement, activity, and dues/fee payment;
* tracking donations and store purchases;
* tracking event attendance and committee membership;
* scheduling volunteer activity;
* tracking proposal submissions for a call-for-proposals;
* tracking online learning participation;
* recording of continuing education credits;
* featuring news articles/press releases related to your association activity;
* accounting;
* responding to your inquiries, and/or other requests or questions; and
* periodically sending you newsletters and other marketing materials.

**Data Retention**  
  
When the purposes of the processing are satisfied, we will purge/anonymize your Personal Data within 6 months.  
  
**Sharing Personal Data with Third Parties**  
  
We may share your Personal Data with other entities. Such third parties may include those providing:

* association management software;
* web development services;
* journal submission software;
* registration management software;
* hosting services;
* cloud storage services;
* IT support services;
* analytics services;
* customer support services;
* payment services; and
* any other type of external services we might need for us to be able to operate our Website and to provide you with our services.

We may share your Personal Data with these third-party vendors, solely to enable them to perform the services for us. In providing such Personal Data, we require that those third-party vendors maintain at least the same level of security that we maintain for such Personal Data.  
  
If we would need to transfer your Personal Data to third countries, we will ensure that this will be subject to appropriate safeguards and other requirements, as stated in the applicable laws.  
  
**Other Disclosure of Your Personal Data**  
  
We may disclose your Personal Data:

* to the extent required by law or if we have a good-faith belief that such disclosure is necessary, in order to comply with official investigations or legal proceedings initiated by governmental and/or law enforcement officials, or private parties, including but not limited to: in response to subpoenas, search warrants, or court orders;
* if we sell or transfer all or a portion of our company’s business interests, assets, or both, or in connection with a corporate merger, consolidation, restructuring, or other company change; and
* to our subsidiaries or affiliates, only if necessary for business and operational purposes.

We reserve the right to use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data, which does not include any Personal Data, about our Website users as a group for any legal business purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers, sponsors, clients, and customers.  
  
If we must disclose your Personal Data, in order to comply with official investigations or legal proceedings initiated by governmental and/or law enforcement officials, we may not be able to ensure that such recipients of your Personal Data will maintain the privacy or security of your Personal Data.  
  
**Your European Rights**  
  
FOR EUROPEAN RESIDENTS ONLY. You have the right to ask us not to process your Personal Data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your Personal Data) if we intend to use your Personal Data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your Personal Data. You can also exercise the right by contacting us using the information in the Contact Us section of this Policy.  
  
Under European data protection law, in certain circumstances, you have the right to:

* **Request access to your Personal Data**. You may have the right to request access to any Personal Data we hold about you as well as related information, including the purposes for processing the Personal Data, the recipients or categories of recipients with whom the Personal Data has been shared, where possible, the period for which the Personal Data will be stored, the source of the Personal Data, and the existence of any automated decision making.
* **Request correction of your Personal Data**. You may have the right to obtain without undue delay the rectification of any inaccurate Personal Data we hold about you.
* **Request erasure of your Personal Data.** You may have the right to request that Personal Data held about you is deleted.
* **Object to processing of your Personal Data.** You may have the right to prevent or restrict processing of your Personal Data.
* **Request restriction of processing your Personal Data Request transfer of your Personal Data.** You may have the right to request transfer of Personal Data directly to a third party where this is technically feasible.
* **Withdraw your consent**

In addition, where you believe that AADSM has not complied with its obligations under this Notice or European law, you have the right to make a complaint to an EU Data Protection Authority, such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office. You can exercise any of these rights by contacting us using the information in the Contact Us section of this Policy.  
  
**Use of Cookies**  
  
A "cookie" is a small file stored on your device which potentially contains (or may be linked to) information about you, your device, and your use of our Website. We may use cookies to enable your use of the Website. The use of cookies is industry standard, so your browser may be set to accept cookies. If you would prefer not to accept cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to reject all cookies or some cookies. Note, if you reject certain cookies, you may not be able to access all of the features of our Website. For more information, please visit https://www.aboutcookies.org/.

We use a number of suppliers that may also set cookies on your device on our behalf when you visit AADSM websites to allow them to deliver the services they are providing. When you visit AADSM websites, you may receive cookies from third-party websites or domains. We endeavor to identify these cookies before they are used so that you can decide whether or not you wish to accept them. NextRoll is utilized by AADSM for some online marketing activities, if you would like to learn more about NextRoll and the California Consumer Privacy Act, please [click here](https://www.nextroll.com/privacy#service-13 "https://www.nextroll.com/privacy#service-13"). You can opt-out of cookie remarketing at any time by the following link: [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2F "http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!%2f").

**Automated Decision-Making**  
  
We do not perform automated decision-making activities, such as profiling.  
  
**Data Integrity and Security**  
  
We have implemented and will maintain technical, organizational, and physical security measures that are reasonably designed to help protect your Personal Data from unauthorized processing, such as unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.  
  
**Access, Correction, and Deletion**  
  
If you are a data subject about whom we store Personal Data, you may have the right to request access to, and the opportunity to update, correct, or delete such Personal Data. You may always email us at the email address found in the Contact Us section of this Policy. We will implement your requested changes, as soon as we reasonably can.  
  
**Restriction and Objection to Processing, Portability**  
  
If you are a data subject whose Personal Data we process, you may have the right to ask that we limit our processing of your Personal Data, as well as the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data. You may also have the right to ask to have your Personal Data exported in a machine-readable format. To exercise such rights, where applicable, please contact us using the information in the Contact Us section of this Policy.  
  
**Privacy of Children**  
  
Our Website is not directed at, or intended for use by, children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly allow anyone under 18 to provide any Personal Data on our Website. Children should always get permission from a parent or guardian, before sending personal information over the Internet. If you believe your child may have provided us with Personal Data, you can contact us using the information in the Contact Us section of this Policy and we will delete that Personal Data.  
  
**Supervisory Authority Oversight**  
  
If you are a data subject whose Personal Data we process, you may also have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection regulator in one or more of the European Union Member States.  
  
**Changes to This Policy**  
  
We may update this Policy from time to time by posting a new version on this web page. You should visit this page occasionally to ensure you agree with any changes. We will post our revised Policy on this web page and update the “Effective” date above to reflect the date of the changes. By continuing to use our Website after we post any such changes, you agree that you accept the Policy as modified.  
  
**Links to Other Sites**  
Our website has links to additional web resources. The privacy policy described here does not necessarily apply to those other sites. Once you link to another site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that site.  

**Contact Us**

If you have a complaint, dispute, or questions regarding this Policy or our treatment of your Personal Data, please contact us at:

_General Contact_

Tracy Murphy

tmurphy@aadsm.org

Please allow up to 30 days for us to reply.

|     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- |
| **Contact Us:** |     |     |     |
| 901 Warrenville Rd. Suite 180  <br>Lisle, IL 60532 | **Email:**  <br>info@aadsm.org | **Phone:**  <br>(630) 686-9875 | **Fax:**  <br>(630) 686-9876 |

© 2024 American Academy of Dental Sleep Medicine  
Website powered by [MemberLeap](https://memberleap.com/)
